Bryce M. Tucker

(503) 860-1901 | Portland OR | bryce.tucker@gmail.com www.brycetucker.net | www.linkedin.com/in/bryce-tucker | www.github.com/BryceT516

Skills Summary:

- Communications: Excellent ability to communicate technical information to non-technical audience, experienced leading team meetings & contract negotiations.
- Leadership: Leadership roles in teams up to 20 people. Adept at inclusion of diverse viewpoints and diplomatic
 facilitation of teamwork. Confident liaison between technical and non-technical stakeholders. Oversaw
 development projects in C#, Java, .Net framework, Enterprise Service Bus methodologies, and SQL databases.
- Financial Management: Annual budgets up to \$12M, 11 yrs managing budgets of increasing size & complexity.
- Programming/Development: C#, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Python 2.x/3.x, Java, C++, Arduino, Ruby, VB.
- Frameworks: .NET Framework, ASP.NET MVC, node.js, Bootstrap, Knockout.js.
- Architectural Paradigms: MVC, Service Oriented Architecture, APIs using REST and JSON Interfaces, MVVM, Dependency Injection, Single Page Applications (SPA).
- Methodologies: SDLC, Agile, Scrum, Waterfall, Project Management Institute Body of Knowledge, ITIL.
- Databases: MS SQL Server, MySQL, sqlite, MS Access, Oracle 12c.
- Operating Systems: Windows, Linux (Ubuntu), OS X, Android.
- IDE: MS Visual Studio, Eclipse, NetBeans.
- Business Domains: Military / Government, Enterprise Content Management, Mission Critical Systems.

Work History:

Prosper IT Consulting
Portland OR
Software Developer Intern
February 2017 - July 2017

- Completed 500 hours of training in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, SQL, Python 2.x/3.x, C#, ASP.NET, and Bootstrap framework.
- Developed inventory control system with C# and ASP.NET MVC Framework to maintain records on product sales and calculate cost versus income and parts used.

United States Coast Guard

Multiple

Officer

May 2005 - July 2016

Command, Control &

Communications Engineering Center Lieutenant (July 2012 – July 2016)

Portsmouth VA

- Project manager of mission critical systems used for law enforcement & life-saving operations.
- Managed \$12 million annual budget and 20 diverse personnel & contractors reporting multiple stakeholders with sometimes competing goals.
- Recommended strategic \$4 million reduction in annual support costs while maintaining operations through improved analysis of support procedures and metrics, then implementing changes based on data.
- Improved delivery of support to users by increasing collaboration between departments.
- Oversaw C# software development using agile methods to improve system functionality & supportability.

Operations Systems Center

Martinsburg WV

Lieutenant (July 2010 – June 2012)

- Project Manager of software development for three mission critical systems that were upgraded while in use for life-saving operations.
- Managed budget of \$2.5M and 13 team members.
- \$200,000 reduction of annual support costs through increased system automation.
- Improved user interface, leading to reduced activity time by 20%, increased data accuracy by 10%.
- Guided development of ASP.NET software using agile methods to iterate improvements & new features.
- Guided team through changing from an email push methodology for GPS location data to a REST API pull paradigm, reduced code base by 30% and improved system reliability and speed.

Operations Systems Center

Martinsburg WV

Lieutenant Junior Grade

(July 2008 - June 2010)

- Managed three enterprise-wide systems with a combined annual budget of \$6.6M and teams up to 15 people.
- Implemented Scrum Agile methods to scale hardware, develop software and transition data.
- Coast Guard CIO gave team rare in-person recognition for delivering the capabilities on time & on budget.
- Standardized website look and feel for the Coast Guard's Internet presence, established processes to ensure
 all units maintained web sites accordingly and implemented new functionality and organization for the CG
 public relations office and Commandant's office.

Electronic Systems Support Unit

Alameda CA

Ensign

(May 2005 - June 2008)

- As Administration Officer, handled administration of 25 personnel and \$1M unit funds and supervised administration personnel.
- Initiated and developed a daily log system using Sharepoint 2008 for the six sections of the unit, increasing collaboration and shared knowledge.
- Project Manager of the Unit's Change of Command ceremony and stood as Master of Ceremonies, for which I
 received recognition from the presiding admiral.

Roadmaster, Inc.

Portland OR

IT Support & Web Developer

Prior 2005

- Updated internal and external website applications used by product dealers and customers.
- Served as on-site IT support at the central office plus three manufacturing and warehousing sites.
- Assisted office personnel with various business software applications and workstations.

Education:

Nova Southeastern University

Ft. Lauderdale FL

MS Computer Science

expected, December 2018

Nova Southeastern University: Specific study area is in real-world computing including courses in software engineering, user interface design and 3D graphics. Have gained a wide understanding of operating systems, object-oriented programming, multi-threaded/multi-process programming, and programming languages. Used Java, JavaScript, and Ruby to complete significant projects for various classes.

The Tech Academy

Portland OR

Portland OR

Software Developer Boot Camp

May 2015 - July 2016

Intensive training with more than 500 hours of instruction and hands-on work in:

Fundamentals of Computer Science, HTML/CSS, JavaScript, C#, Python, ASP.NET, web application development, object-oriented programming, Agile/Scrum, source control, relational database design and management, SQL programming and more. Completed practical projects.

Portland State University

BS Computer Engineering &

Physics

graduated, December 2002

Completed courses in Computer Science, Electrical Engineering, and Physics to gain a comprehensive view of computer systems both hardware and software. Received an IEEE student award for work with the IEEE student chapter and setting up a new robotics lab for research projects.

Certifications:

Project Management Institute

Project Management Professional Certification (1910704)

February 2016

The Scrum Alliance

ScrumMaster Certification

February 2017